[Applauding]
[Man]
And the only thing wrong-
The only thing wrong
with the American dream...
is people-
too many people-
too many of us telling young people
that the dream is dead.
They told me that
when I was growing up
in the slums ofTrenton.
[Audience Grumbling]
And they were wrong.
They told me that
when I decided to run for senator,
with only $58 in my savings account.
And they were wrong.
And they are still telling me that now-
that I don't have a chance because I'm black,
because I don't have the right nose,
because I still only have $58
in my savings account.
[Laughing]
With your help,
we can keep that dream alive.
And in closing,
just...
let me say-
Let me say that you should all
donate the legal maximum...
to the next president
of the United States.
Are you okay? Do you need
some water or something?
No. I'm fine. I'm fine, really.
Handsome guy like you,
I bet you get 70% of the women.
Well, here's hoping.
Of course, it helps
your wife died of cancer.
I mean, I'm sorry,
but the sympathy vote's
in your pocket.
Yeah, I appreciate your support.
[Echoing]
Listen, Senator, my union
has a hell of a war chest.
Um, I've always been strong
on the union.
The thing is, you always go on
in your speeches about the workers...
in Indonesia, Cambodia, Timbuktu.
Because I think we have a-
a moral-
My union members are hurting.
They don't care about
moral this and moral that.
Are you all right?
- Senator?
- Ugh. Hey!
The guys are gonna love that.
[Man]
Everyone, give him some room.
Give him room to breathe!
Back off, please!
Senator, are you all right?
[Vogler]
The senator's suffering from nausea,
headache and mental confusion.
Ah, bad sushi
is so hard to diagnose.
You're being childish.
Look, ifhis case is as trivial
as you think, it'll take you
three minutes to diagnose.
Uh-huh. Three minutes that I
could spend sitting on the toilet
with the funny pages.
- You're mad at me.
- Nope.
I never liked Cameron or Foreman.
You know why I'm forcing you
to fire one of them? Because you need
to prove to me that you're a team player.
Now, if you did that,
you wouldn't need to go
through this exercise.
Fine. I'll hold the senator's hair
while he upchucks.
Oh, and, uh, by the way,
I need you to give a speech
at the National Cardiology Conference,
um, next week.
I don't do speeches. I'm shy.
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals
has developed a new ACE inhibitor.
I would like you to extol the virtues
of this breakthrough medication.
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals?
Wait a second?
Don't I own that company?
Oh, no, that's right. You do.
Viopril is a significant improvement
over the old version.
It's all there in the study.
I know its price tag
is significantly improved.
[Sighs]
You can either give one 10-minute talk
and one three-minute diagnosis,
or you can fire one of your pets.
My understanding was that you believed
in rationality above all else.
Viopril.
[Senator]
I appreciate your keeping
the media away.
We're keeping
your staff away as well.
Take it easy now.
- I'm in the middle of a campaign.
- The faster we can get you better,
the faster you can get out of here.
Anyone else
at the fund-raiser get sick?
I don't think so, and I don't think that's it.
I've been under the weather for weeks.
Lots of traveling. I'm supposed
to be in the Sudan next week.
- [Electronic Beeping]
- Oh!
Helps me concentrate.
- [Bottle Lid Pops]
- Even better than drugs.
Open your mouth, please.
Ahh.
That's quite a scar.
When I was six, I fell off the swing
and bit my tongue.
Couldn't talk right
for the longest time.
[Chuckling]
Lots of teasing.
It just made me fight harder,
speak up for those who can't.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Tongues heal too fast.
Your political consultants
have written you a nice story.
In a tight race, the lispers alone
could put you over the top.
You a Republican,
or you just hate all politicians?
I just find being forced
to sit through drivel annoying.
You find sincerity annoying?
You're a black kid from the ghetto...
who made it to Yale Law
and the United States Senate.
That's a sufficiently mythical story.
You don't need to lie about your tongue.
Must've missed it.
What's wrong?
What is it?
It's not the food.
It's your brain.
Get an M.R.I.
And a lumbar puncture.
Cancel your travel plans.
The senator's L.P.
Showed no sign of infection,
and the M.R.I. Looks fairly clean.
I guess we can tell him
he's fairly healthy and can go home.
Well, there is something
in Broca's area,
but it's small,
low intensity.
Most likely
just background noise.
Care to bet your job on that?
What was that?
What was what?
You got annoyed.
That was clearly
an annoyed face.
I get annoyed by glib remarks
about our futures.
Last week you didn't get annoyed.
You made poopie in your pants.
It's weird.
It's almost like now you know
you have nothing to worry about.
Chase has nothing
to worry about?
None of you has anything
to worry about.
What happened?
Vogler saw the error of his ways
and repented.
The lesion could be nothing.
Also could be a brain tumor
or an infection.
There's only one way
to find out which.
You want to cut into his brain?
Dangerous, I know.
Especially since he's a politician,
his brain's all twisted.
But I weighed that against the risk
of him stroking out before lunch.
Call Surgery. Get it scheduled.
- You're not pregnant.
- Well, I told you that.
There's got to be some other reason
I'm still spotting.
Sure. You were pregnant.
Based on your hormone levels,
you've had a miscarriage.
I haven't even been on a date.
Right. And since
it's physically impossible to have sex
without someone buying you dinner-
I haven't had sex
since I split up with my husband.
- That was almost a year ago.
- Fine. Have it your way.
Immaculate conception.
- Um, what do I do?
- Well, it's obvious.
Start a religion.
In my office.
Afternoon delight.
She just loves the hard wood.
You're not doing a brain biopsy
based on a spot on an M.R.I.
[Throws File Down]
Where'd you get that?
Not on a United States senator.
Oh, just so I'm clear-
If he was a janitor, that would be okay?
Do you have a list?
A brain biopsy can cause
permanent neurological damage.
Uh-huh. Whereas tumors
are really good for brains.
Make 'em grow big and strong.
- It's my call.
- No, it's not.
- You're pulling rank on patient care?
- It's not my call either.
- It's up to you.
- Either it's a tumor or it's an infection
that the lumbar puncture didn't pick up.
Either way,
unless we treat it immediately,
it could kill you.
Or it could be nothing.
Reading brain M.R.I.'s
is not an exact science.
Well, what caused my s-symptoms?
Wow! Excellent question.
Many doctors wouldn't
have gone there.
It could be
a transient ischemic attack.
You could make the argument
for watching carefully
for the time being.
Hmm, but you'd only make that argument
if you were an administrator
covering your ass.
That's absurd and insulting.
Insulting, yes.
What would the voters think?
If they find out
I've had a b-brain biopsy?
This could leave you
b-b-b-brain damaged,
and you're worried
about NASCAR dads?
[Whirring]
It's not a brain tumor.
It's not a bacterial infection either.
So you biopsied his brain
for nothing?
If that were true,
would Dr. Wilson's mouth
be contorted into that ugly shape?
It's toxoplasmosis.
You sure?
Which means the Great Black Hope
has full-blown Al DS.
They're gonna love that
in Dubuque.
Toxoplasmosis
is a fairly common fungus
you can get...
from eating under-cooked meat
or touching cat feces.
In rare cases,
the fungi travel up the bloodstream
and latch onto the brain,
causing a lesion
or inflammation.
So, what's the prognosis?
Toxo usually responds
to treatment,
but it only causes a lesion in your brain
if your immune system is extremely weak
to begin with.
Senator, I'm afraid you have Al DS.
- [Scoffs]
- As I'm sure-
No!
As I'm sure you know,
people with H.I.V. Can live a long time.
- What else could do this to me?
- Theoretically, certain cancers.
If you have toxo in your brain,
you have AIDS.
I do not have Al DS.
I don't sh- sh- shoot up drugs.
I don't s-sleep with-
This is very bad news.
I get that, and I sympathize.
But we gotta speed through
the denial phase because you need
antiretrovirals and you need them fast.
But-You haven't even
tested me for H.I.V.!
- We will.
- But the toxo drugs
are gonna piss off your fungi.
And when fungi get pissed-
- [Clattering]
- I am not going to take the pills.
You're afraid word will leak out.
Trust me. You're not gonna
be president either way.
They don't call it the White House
because of the paint job.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You're gonna give me the drugs
for the toxo only.
You're going to test me for H.I.V.,
under a false name.
You are going to test me for cancer...
and anything else
that could have done this to me.
If I have cancer,
I will deal with it.
But I do not...
have Al DS.
"Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals
are pleased to announce...
that Dr. Gregory House
will present the latest research
on our exciting new ACE inhibitor."
[Scoffs]
You're making that up.
That's Vogler's company.
Press release.
"During an address at the North
American Cardiology Conference."
- House never gives speeches.
- But when I really believe in something-
Gosh dang it, I got a chance
to make a difference here.
You made a deal with Vogler?
It's all the rage.
Everybody's doing it.
So, what's the deal?
You get to keep all of us
if you flog his products?
One speech. No biggie.
Foreman's doing a bone marrow biopsy
to check for cancer.
Cancer?
The senator's got Al DS.
Cancer sounds better
in a press release.
I need you guys to rush
the ELISA test for H.I.V.
Thank you.
For the speech.
When I said rush,
I meant, you know, fast.
- "Stat's" the word you doctors use, right?
- I know it's hard for you.
Double stat?
[Moans Quietly]
This may sting a little.
Sorry.
[Coughs]
It wasn't the shot.
It's, um- My head's killing me.
Senator, we don't have
to do this now.
We can hold off
till your H.I.V. Test comes back.
[Laughing]
Because you figure
it's gonna come back positive.
In my experience-
Patients lie.
Politicians lie more.
Black politicians-
Oh. I don't think black politicians lie
more than white politicians.
- We lie less.
- You figure we're morally superior?
[Chuckling]
I've got my theories.
No, we-
we just can't get away with it.
[Clears Throat]
No one's gonna g-give us
the benefit of the doubt.
No one's gonna cut us
a second chance.
And when it happens,
it's not just a- a bad politician.
It's- It's a bad role model.
It's a- a dis-
discredit to the race.
You ready?
Yeah.
Take a deep breath.
[Grunts]
[Gasping]
Dr. House, I just wanted-
You're welcome again.
I want you to know how much-
Got it. You're grateful.
Apparently you seem to think
it will mean a lot to me to know that.
Do you know why people
pray to God?
I thought
you didn't believe in God.
I don't.
Well, then you better be making
a very good point.
Do you think they pray to him
and praise him because they want him
to know how great he is?
God already knows that.
Are you comparing me to God?
I mean, that's great,
but just so you know,
I've never made a tree.
I thank you because
it means something to me...
to be grateful
for what I receive.
You are the most naive atheist
I've ever met.
Dr. House, you have
a patient in room one.
Thank God.
People pray so that God
won't crush them like bugs.
I'm not gonna crush you.
"Petechial" bruising?
I don't know if I pronounced that right.
Gosh, the Internet
is such a wonderful tool.
It could be leukemia.
Definitely possible.
The more likely diagnosis
is hickey.
Well, it can't be a hickey.
Why is everybody so ashamed of sex
all of a sudden?
I'm not having sex.
I've barely even thought about sex
since my marriage. Ow!
I say you're having sex,
you say you're not.
Either you're lying
or I'm wrong.
- Or there's some middle ground.
- You mean, like, oral?
I mean, you're having sex
without knowing it.
I'm testing you for booze,
drugs and G.H.B.
I don't drink or-What's G.H.B.?
The date-rape drug.
It's positive.
Your "T" cell count is eight,
which means
there's a good chance you'll die.
I'm telling you this because we need
to contact your sexual partners.
I've only had two girlfriends.
Two. After my wife died.
I used c-condoms.
You know the chances of you getting H.I. V.
From heterosexual sex with a condom?
Yes.
Someday there will be
a black president.
a gay president.
Maybe there'll even be
a gay, black president.
But one combination
I do not see happening
is gay, black and dead.
You need to stop lying to me.
It must be miserable,
always assuming the worst in people.
Cut the crap. You're dying.
And you're clever, you're witty
and you are a coward.
You're scared of taking chances.
- I take chances all the time.
It's one of my worst qualities.
- On people?
Wanting to believe
the best about people
doesn't make it true.
Being afraid to believe it
doesn't make it false.
Well, that's very moving.
It's a shame I don't vote.
Hmm.
This is who I am.
I believe in people.
I'm not hiply cynical,
and I don't make easy, snide remarks.
I would rather think that people are good
and be disappointed once and again.
I need to draw some more blood.
Nurse!
The antiretrovirals aren't working.
That's not surprising.
He's just gonna keep getting worse.
You realize that, right?
Why are you spying on my case?
Why are you giving
that speech next week?
We're both just doing
what we have to do.
You don't see a problem with that?
Checking in on a patient?
Yeah, wow. How do I look
myself in the mirror?
You're not the one being asked
to perpetrate a fraud
on the American people.
It's a 10-minute speech.
That I've been ordered to give.
Vogler's drug works.
Don't care.
Why do you have to make
everything so dramatic?
I'm a very high-strung little lap dog.
[Growls, Yipping, Growls]
[Barks]
[Grunting]
Uh-uh. No pills.
What's going on?
The antiretrovirals
aren't working.
Why not?
Because you don't have Al DS.
The first test was a false positive.
Happens one time in every 5,000.
You r-ran a second test?
- Yeah.
You're still dying.
The only difference is,
now we don't know why.
He's continuing to lose control
of the muscles on his right side.
- His brain is getting foggier,
and his "T" cells are still in single digits.
- Why are we doing this here?
So Cuddy can't find us.
Unless we figure out
the underlying disease,
this guy's lied to his last constituent.
- False negative
on the P.C.R. Al DS test?
- Ran it twice.
- Immunoglobulin deficiency?
- No history of respiratory problems.
Idiopathic "T" cell deficiency.
Idiopathic- from the Latin
meaning "we're idiots" 'cause we
can't figure out what's causing it.
[Sighs]
Give him a whole body scan.
- You hate whole body scans.
- 'Cause they're useless.
Could probably scan any one of us
and find five different doodads
that look like cancer.
But when you're fourth down
and a hundred to go, in the snow,
you don't call
a running play up the middle,
unless you're theJets.
I hate sports metaphors.
Why did you order
the second AIDS test?
Standard procedure.
Oh, well, that's you-
Mr. Standard Procedure.
You suspected the first test
was a false positive?
I knew he was going to Africa,
and I figured he was vaccinated
for Hep "A" and "B."
That could cause a false positive.
- You knew that before you ordered
the first test. What changed?
- I should have ordered both.
You were sure he had Al DS.
Then you talked to him,
then you had doubts.
What did he say?
He said he had not engaged
in any risky behavior.
Huh. And you believed him.
He didn't have any reason to lie.
Everybody lies, except politicians?
House,
I believe you're a romantic.
You didn't just believe him,
you believed in him!
Do you want to come over tonight
and watch old movies and cry?
Dr. Cameron's getting to you.
Well, I guess you can't
be around that much niceness
and not get any on you.
Is that why you haven't put
the moves on her?
What makes you think
I haven't put the moves on her?
Oh! Oh, boy! You're in trouble.
[Door Opens]
You have restored my faith
in the human race.
- You're lying.
- No. I'm not lying.
Just got your results back.
No G.H.B., no nothing.
It means you're having sex
and you're lying about it.
No. And I have a new symptom.
I have a rash on my butt.
[Chuckles]
Do you wanna? Yeah.
- What is it?
- It's a carpet burn.
No. It can't be.
Doctor, I love sex.
I miss it.
I haven't had any in over a year.
Well, you managed to keep
this appointment, so you have
no short-term memory problem.
Multiple personalities?
Do you find yourself
losing chunks of time?
Do you wake up, and you don't
remember falling asleep?
No. I just wake up really exhausted.
- Something upsetting you?
- No.
My ex lives
in the apartment downstairs.
He's always calling me,
always wanting to get back together,
complaining about mixed signals.
"Get out of my life. '"
How much clearer can you get?
We have a sleep lab
in the basement.
If nothing else, it will get you away
from your ex for a night.
Slightly enlarged lymph node
in his left armpit.
How slightly?
Quarter mil.
- Lymphoma?
- [House] Sure.
Or he's had a cold
in the last six months.
- What, you got her on speed dial?
- I just follow the scent of arrogance.
Another slightly enlarged node over here.
Two more in his neck and one in his groin.
- And there's a cyst in his liver.
- [Cameron] It looks complex.
Central necrosis?
[House]
Spontaneous bleeding.
It's benign.
I was rooting for a really cool tumor.
Instead we're stuck with this crap.
Doesn't matter. Once you find 'em,
you gotta check 'em.
Knock yourselves out.
I just saw Senator Wright.
He looks like hell.
That sushi must've been
a lot worse than you thought.
Mr. Vogler, would you like
a free whole body scan?
A man of your stature
should get himself checked
at least three times a year.
Here's a few key points
I want you to cover
during your speech.
[House]
Fourteen pages.
The audience will be comatose
by paragraph two.
Throw in a joke.
Dr. Chase, we need to talk.
- How do you see this ending?
- What ending?
I can't fire you,
so you have no reason to fear me
and, therefore, no reason to lie to me.
You told Cuddy where I was.
You told Vogler what I was doing.
Yeah.
So how can I work with you?
Well, you don't have a choice.
[Foreman]
This might hurt a little.
- Lie to me.
- [Chuckles]
Okay.
It'll feel like a gentle massage.
House...
is a lousy teacher.
You can't lie for beans.
Have you ever told
any really big ones?
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
I might be messed up,
but I'm not that out of it.
- [Grunting]
- [Foreman] Strap his arm down.
Am I going to be okay?
I hope so.
I am selling my soul.
Just a little piece.
And you are getting
something in return.
I said I was selling it.
Didn't say I was giving it away.
That would be immoral
and stupid.
All they've done
is add an antacid.
Does it work?
That's not the point.
Of course it's the point.
He's not asking you to lie.
He's not asking you
to do something illegal.
He's not asking me to do anything.
He's not ordering you.
He gave you a choice.
You chose your staff.
I know this isn't easy for you.
You'll suffer.
Vicodin sales in Jersey will triple.
But you are doing a good thing.
Only you could feel like crap
about doing something good.
Kidney and liver cysts are both benign,
and the lymph nodes all came back clean.
- His left armpit node has antibodies for C.D. 11.
- Not enough to indicate lymphoma.
We never tested
for hairy cell leukemia.
No, but we would have
picked it up somewhere else
besides one lymph node.
- And his spleen isn't enlarged.
- Size isn't everything.
The spleen is the mother lode
for hairy cells.
[Sighs]
Let's cut it open.
You can't biopsy his spleen.
It'll bleed like stink.
In the senator's condition,
a spleen biopsy could easily
cause sepsis and kill him.
Why do you do this to me?
Now if I kill him,
I can't tell the judge I had no idea
of the risks involved.
His brain is turning into mush,
and he's at risk for more infections.
We have to do it.
See? That'll sound
much better in court.
Okay. Go tell our human pincushion
we'll be sticking him one more time.
Cuddy.
Don't you hate doing this?
Yeah.
What's up?
You like me.
Why?
That's kind of a sad question.
I'm just trying to figure out
what makes you tick.
I am not warm and fuzzy,
and you are basically a stuffed animal
made by Grandma.
I don't think
that's why you're asking.
- I think this is because of the speech.
- God, don't try and pick me apart.
Then why are you asking?
What do you want to hear?
[Opens Door]
[Sighs]
Hey, Senator. We need to do
one more biopsy- on your spleen.
[Clears Throat]
I'll have to sign lefty.
My fingers aren't working.
[Coughing]
Have you been coughing a lot?
[Gasps]
Does it hurt?
It's like I can't get air.
Is that from the toxo?
No. This is-This is new.
You don't need to sign.
We can't do the biopsy.
[Coughing, Gasping]
The senator's breathing
is severely impaired.
His O2 sat levels are at 89.
His silver stain indicates
Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia.
Another killer fungus.
It's consistent
with hairy cell leukemia.
[Foreman]
But we can't biopsy his spleen.
Respiratory distress.
His platelets are 20 and dropping.
His blood won't clot worth a damn.
[Cameron]
There's gotta be another way
to diagnose hairy cell.
No. His bone marrow's indeterminate.
Spleen biopsy's the only way to go.
You know, when the Inuit go fishing,
they don't look for fish.
Why, Dr. House?
They look for the blue heron
because there's no way to see the fish.
But if there's fish,
there's gonna be birds fishing.
Now, if he's got hairy cell,
what else should we see circling overhead?
- He should have all sorts of weird viruses.
- H.T.L.V. And A.T.L.V.
We can test for them.
Run the titers.
These were your brain waves
at 2:45 a.m.
Now, here it comes.
There's an abruptjump
from slow-wave sleep.
This indicates
partial sleep arousal.
Most common type is somnambulism.
Sleepwalking.
That would explain why
I'm so tired when I wake up.
Yes. And also why
you were pregnant.
And the hickeys.
And the carpet burn.
I had sex in my sleep?
Sexsomnia
is a documented disorder.
You said your ex lives downstairs.
I'll kill him.
Okay. But he probably didn't know
that you were asleep.
Sexsomniacs
can act pretty normal.
I'm gonna write you a prescription
for a low-dose antidepressant.
It'll let you sleep better.
If you wanna save yourself the $15 co-pay,
you could have sex while you're awake.
- He's my ex. I don't-
- You live in the same building.
You haven't had sex
with anyone else for a year.
You sleepwalk right into his arms.
Call me crazy,
but I'm sensing unresolved issues.
Negative
for H.T.L.V. 1 and 2.
And negative for A.T.L.V.
And everything else.
It's not hairy cell.
Hey. You really
gonna give that speech?
You got an opinion too?
I'm a little surprised.
Frankly, I thought you were too much
of a self-absorbed ass to do this for us.
You're welcome.
He's positive for Epstein-Barr.
So what?
It doesn't point to hairy cell.
It's irrelevant.
[Gasping]
Hey.
You didn't fall off the swings
when you were eight.
[Gasping Continues]
S-S-Six.
Ever.
Give that back.
Uh-uh. We have to talk.
You had an epileptic seizure.
That's how you bit your tongue.
L-I haven't had a seizure since-
What medication did you take?
No s-s-seizure since I was six.
No dr-dr-drugs s-since I was 10.
Yeah, that's it. Don't worry about
what the question is.
Don't worry that you're
starting to feel dizzy.
Just stay on message.
[Gasping]
My-
[Sobbing]
My mother used to call it-
[Gasping]
"Funny-something."
- Phenytoin?
- Yes!
Okay, okay. You're okay.
It's okay.
[Whimpering]
Everybody lies.
[House]
Senator Gary H. Wright of NewJersey
had childhood epilepsy.
He took phenytoin.
That drug,
with the Epstein-Barr virus,
is associated with common variable
immunodeficiency disease.
"T" cells down, "B" cells down.
Keeps you from forming
enough antibodies.
See, the antibodies are basically
your defensive line.
And your brain
is like the quarterback.
And then the fungi
are like blitzing linebackers
plunging up the middle.
Your lungs are like-
Okay, you got two quarterbacks.
[Chase]
C. V.I.D.?
That's a type
of immunoglobulin deficiency.
I said that.
Yeah. Well, it was a stupid idea
when you said it.
Then he got the respiratory problem,
and he tested positive for Epstein-Barr.
That's pretty much
a childhood disease.
That's another reason why
Chase's suggestion was idiotic.
He got it when he was a kid.
He didn't get
any symptoms until now.
It happens.
It gets triggered by stress-
like public speaking.
So you're basing your diagnosis
on a virus that's relatively common
and a drug he took 30 years ago.
Start the senator
on I.V. Immunoglobulin, stat.
Lfhe gets better, I'm right.
Lfhe dies, you're right.
Dr. House?
You faked that.
No.
Say "antiretroviral."
Antiretroviral.
Now, say it three times fast.
We just got your latest blood results.
Your white cells are up.
Your "T" cells
are back over a hundred.
That's-That's good, right?
In a week? That's terrific.
You'll need medication
for the rest of your life,
but other than that, you're fine.
Am I well enough
to run for president?
- Why not run for pope
while you're at it?
- Oh, come on.
Kennedy had Addison's. F.D.R. Had polio.
Two of the best presidents
in the last hundred years.
If they were running today,
they wouldn't stand a chance.
[Chuckling]
You figure you'd be surgeon general
if you didn't have the limp?
No. There's things I can't do.
And like you said,
I... have to live with reality.
Well, then I'm running.
Good for you.
Now, don't get excited.
He's right. I, uh- I won't win.
Then why run?
Oh, I see. Your point being,
the only way to make a difference
is to win every fight.
But, hey, why listen to me?
I own the company.
I'm certainly not to be trusted, right?
[Laughter]
Dr. Greg House,
on the other hand,
has a reputation...
for integrity,
among other things.
[Scattered Laughing]
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dr. Greg House.
[Electronic Feedback Hums]
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals'
extraordinary commitment
to research excellence...
is exemplified
by their new ACE inhibitor,
a breakthrough medical approach
that will protect millions
from heart disease.
That's not a speech.
I thought it was pithy.
You got enough
for a press release anyhow.
Foreman or Cameron.
[Chuckles]
A few things I forgot to mention.
Ed Vogler
is a brilliant businessman,
a brilliant judge of people...
and a man
who has never lost a fight.
You know how I know
that the new ACE inhibitor is good?
'Cause the old one was good.
The new one is really the same,
just more expensive.
A lot more expensive.
You see, that's another example
of Ed's brilliance.
Whenever one ofhis drugs
is about to lose its patent,
he has his boys and girls
alter itjust a tiny bit,
patent it all over again,
making not just a pointless new pill,
but millions and millions of dollars.
Which is good for everybody, right?
Except the patients.
But- [Scoffs] who cares?
They're just so damn sick.
God obviously
never liked them anyway.
All the healthy people in the room,
let's have a big round of applause
for Ed Vogler.
[House Applauding]
I threw in a joke.
~ [Piano]
[Knocking]
I'm sorry.
I should've taken an extra couple
of Vicodin and just held my nose.
- I'm guessing you did take
a couple extra Vicodin.
- True.
You don't need to worry
about firing anyone.
I'm leaving.
Why?
Is this another noble,
self-sacrificing gesture?
Are you trying
to protect Foreman?
No.
So this is just,
"Don't fire me. I quit"?
I'm protecting myself.
You asked me why I like you.
You're abrasive and rude.
But I figured, everything you do,
you do it to help people.
But I was wrong.
You do it because it's right.
There are only two ways
that I can deal with things.
One is in my control.
That's to leave.
Good-bye, House.
That's some bad hat, Harry.
www.tvsubtitles.net